Guide to the Clarence Stein papers, 1905-1983.
Stein, Clarence papers
- Series VII. Photographs
  - 1 nitrate negative American Pacific grocery store c. 1928 (Box 21, Folder 83a)
  - 1 nitrate negative building [industrial] radial corners, decorative forms, surface patterns (Box 21, Folder 84a)
  - 2 nitrate negatives farm house grouping (Box 21, Folder 85a *)
  - 3 nitrate negatives English Sq. /Fountain/ children dressed in middies (Box 21, Folder 87a)
  - 5 nitrate negatives High rise apartments England (Box 21, Folder 88a)
  - 1 nitrate negative outdoor billboard England (Box 21, Folder 89a)
  - 1 nitrate negative England, street & courtyard 1 nitrate negative old industrial building c.1930 (Box 21, Folder 90a 91a)
  - 1 nitrate negative construction of building c.1930 (Box 21, Folder 92a)
  - 3 nitrate negatives Amber- India 1930 (Box 21, Folder 93a)
  - 2 nitrate negatives India 1930 (Box 21, Folder 94a)
  - 3 nitrate negatives India 1930 (Box 21, Folder 95a)
  - 4 nitrate negatives India - Jaipur 1930 (Box 21, Folder 96a)
  - 3 nitrate negatives India - Jaipur 1930 (Box 21, Folder 97a)
  - 3 nitrate negatives Jaipur, marketplace, animals, people 1930 (Box 21, Folder 98a)
  - 3 nitrate negatives Udaipur, animals, wagons, urban activity 1930 (Box 21, Folder 99a)
  - 3 nitrate negatives similar subjects to 99a vernacular architectural forms (Box 21, Folder 100a)
  - 3 nitrate negatives architectural forms in Udaipur, India 1930 (Box 21, Folder 101a)
  - 3 nitrate negatives Udaipur, architecture 1930 (Box 21, Folder 102a)
  - 1 nitrate negative India prople [friends] 1930 (Box 21, Folder 103a)
  - Roll negatives, 35 mm. nitrate negatives descriptions of 104-115 listed in index for box 23 of collection #3600 p. (Box 21, Folder 104a-115a*)
  - 1 nitrate negative "Aline 's favorite picture" 1935-36 (Box 21, Folder 120a)
  - 35 mm. rolled negatives "1000 Years" metal box "A" and "B" 1937-43 (Box 21, Folder 121a)
  - 35 mm. rolled negatives "1000 Years" metal box "A" and "B" 1937-43 (Box 21, Folder 122a *)
  - 35 mm. rolled negatives "1000 Years" metal box "A" and "B" 1937-43 (Box 21, Folder 125a)
  - 35 mm. rolled negatives "1000 Years" metal box "A" and "B" 1937-43 (Box 21, Folder 126a *)
  - 13 nitrate negatives U.S.S.R. 1927 (Box 21, Folder 130a)
  - 8 nitrate negatives U.S.S.R 1927 (Box 21, Folder 131a *)
  - 1 nitrate negative interior with stone fireplace (Box 21, Folder 142a)
  - Nitrate rolled negatives metal boxes "A" and "B" "Thousand Years" 1937-43 (Box 21, Folder 143a *)
  - 1 nitrate negative S. Marco, Venice (Box 21, Folder 150a)
  - 1 nitrate negative Plan of S. Marco (Box 21, Folder 151a *)
  - 1 35 mm. roll dancing and ceremonial Bali 1936 (Box 21, Folder 180a)
  - London 1958 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - California (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Europe (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - N.Y.C., Aline & Clarence Stein (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Wylyes England 1949 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Description L. A., Morrison Date 1951 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - 1000 Years (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Kitimat (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Germany and England 1949 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Coral Gables, 1945; Greenhill, Ohio, 1944 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Paris, Clarence Stein (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Nancy and Florence (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - N.Y.C. and 1000 Years (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Paris and Versailles (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Aline's Swiss trip/8 prints 1 5/8"x2 1/2" glaciers, Mr. Blanc, Mer de glace, Sornengrat June 26, 1921 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Dog on Adirondack Trip 1 print Sept. 30, 1921 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Atlantic City [family] 2 prints August 1919 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Atlantic City [family] 2 prints August 1919 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Granny in wicker rocker 1 print May 1921 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - 3 prints [family members] interiors c.May 1921 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - 1 print [Canada Kodaks on canoe trip] notation in C. S. Stein album item #21 c. Sept. 1917 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - 1 print [2 family members or friends in front of lodge] Adirondacks c. Sept. 1921 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - 1 print [family member] Miami, Fla. Dec. 1920 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - 1 print [family group] c. 1918-21 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - 1 positive print young boy with pipe-interior r c.1921 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - 2 positive prints Muz & Dad April 1921 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - 1 positive print Aline April 1921 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - 3 positive prints Muz April 1921 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Contact prints (9) C.S. Stein at his desk, Bali 1936 (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Contact prints (6) Clarence Stein trip 19-35-36 (Box 23, Folder 33i)
  - Contact prints (15) C.S. Stein, Aline M.S., Shirley Alcott 'S.S. Dempo,' Java Dec. 1935 (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - 8 contact prints [Aline & Clarence Stein] (Box 23, Folder 34i)
  - Contact prints (12) S.S. Dempo nursery & dining room Jan. 1936 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - Contact prints (13) Trip en route to Far East [Bali?, Aline] individuals: L. S. Stein, Aline MacMahon Stein, Norma N., E. N. Nov. 1935-Jan. 19 (Box 23, Folder 36)
  - Contact prints (5) Cairo (en route to Java) Dec. 31, 1935 (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - Contact prints (12) Sultan's Palace, Djokjavan 1936 (Box 23, Folder 38)
  - Contact prints (8) Java [building forms; native, modern, bamboo bridges] 1936 (Box 23, Folder 39)
  - Contact prints (8) Singapore, Island sunset Jan. 1936 (Box 23, Folder 40)
  - Contact prints (5) construction, Bali Far East Trip 1936 (Box 23, Folder 41)
  - Contact prints (8) Java marketplace, Eastern trip 1936 (Box 23, Folder 42)
  - Contact prints (7) Java [Temple shrines] 1936 (Box 23, Folder 43)
  - Contact prints (10) Java [Native activities tea picking, rice fields & terraces, batiking bamboo carry] 1936 (Box 23, Folder 44)
  - Contact prints (20) [Misc. Far Eastern Trip] Bali 1936 (Box 23, Folder 45)
  - (10) contact prints (Box 23, Folder 45i)
  - 1 print Hudson Guild Farm, dining hall (1-1) April 1922 (Box 23, Folder 57)
  - 3 prints Bersford, England churchyard, alms house (VI-1, VI-2, V-5) May 22, 23, 1922 (Box 23, Folder 58)
  - 3 prints Chipping-Camden (IV-4) South Entrance to the church; Welewyn, New Town Farm Guild old barn, 17th c. (II-l); Worcester, an old court May 21, 1922May 13, 1922 May 20, 1922 (Box 23, Folder 59)
  - 6 prints, Welwyn, England, Newtown Guild May 13, 1922 (Box 23, Folder 60)
  - 1 print, Wolth & Stow - London, old houses near guild houses May 1922 (Box 23, Folder 61)
  - 3 prints Higham Hill, England, Walthamston, London May 1922 (Box 23, Folder 62)
  - 5 prints Eveslam, England, old house May 20, 1922 (Box 23, Folder 63)
  - 1 print family and friends, spring picnic (Box 23, Folder 68)
  - 4 prints C. S. Stein working, 'tropical' courtyard, sketch of elevation on back of 1 print (Box 23, Folder 70)
  - 1 print C. S. Stein? on building site/stone building (Box 23, Folder 71)
  - 6 prints The Hague, Village of Schevenengen, Amsterdam, public housing & open courts June 1922 (Box 23, Folder 72)
  - 2 prints new brick buildings/multi-family [Holland?] ornamental use of brick, relief pattern (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - 5 prints multi-family dwelling units gardens [Holland or England] 1922 (Box 23, Folder 74)
  - 1 print planned housing, desert c.1918 (Box 23, Folder 75)
  - 16 prints housing in the Southwest, desert and mountain site late 1920's or early 1930's (Box 23, Folder 76)
  - 12 prints (same as 76) (Box 23, Folder 77)
  - 3 prints India/Ellora 1930 (Box 23, Folder 78)
  - 5 prints [England] 1922 (Box 23, Folder 79)
  - 3 prints surface patterns, arches [Aline?] (Box 23, Folder 81)
  - 6 prints American housing (Box 23, Folder 82)
  - 1 print American Pacific Grocery Store produce display c.1928 (Box 23, Folder 83)
  - 2 prints wall, India 1930 (Box 23, Folder 86)
  - 3 prints England [1922] (Box 23, Folder 87)
  - 4 prints High rise residential apartments [England] (Box 23, Folder 88)
  - 1 print outdoor billboards [England] (Box 23, Folder 89)
  - 1 print old industrial building/on water trip abroad c.1930 (Box 23, Folder 91)
  - 33 prints (total) India, see Box 21 descriptions 1930 (Box 23, Folder 93-103)
  - 13 contact prints California Beach, Mission c. 1930-40 (Box 23, Folder 104)
  - 18 contact prints friends, Aline, interior California c. 1930-1940 (Box 23, Folder 105)
  - 9 contact prints friends, Aline, California c. 1930-1940 (Box 23, Folder 106)
  - 17 contact prints patio, garden, friends c. 1930-1940 (Box 23, Folder 107)
  - 4 contact prints prize fight c. 1930-1940 (Box 23, Folder 108)
  - 18 contact prints Clarence and friends on patio c. 1930-1940 (Box 23, Folder 109)
  - 5 contact prints Aline and friends c. 1930-1940 (Box 23, Folder 110)
  - 15 contact prints pets: black cocker spaniel & tiger cat c. 1930-1940 (Box 23, Folder 111)
  - 15 contact prints friend [family member?] California c. 1930-1940 (Box 23, Folder 112)
  - 9 contact prints friend [family member?] California c. 1930-1940 (Box 23, Folder 113)
  - 12 contact prints friends, California c. 1930-1940 (Box 23, Folder 114)
  - 12 contact prints California's landscapes c.1930-1940 (Box 23, Folder 115)
  - 3 damaged prints, 1 torn in half, subject: Bowhodur, Java, 1936; 2 of Udaipur: condition: brittle & torn, 1930 (Box 23, Folder 116)
  - 4 prints: C. S. Stein, 1911; on patio, c.1940; NYC overlooking Hudson River and George Washington Bridge, c.1955; passport photo, c.1970 (Box 23, Folder 117)
  - 2 duplicates of c.1970 passport photo (Box 23, Folder 118)
  - 3 prints views from the Stein apartment, 1 West 64th St., NYC, looking southeast; Benton MacKaye on the balcony c.1935 (Box 23, Folder 119)
  - 5 prints '1000 Years' Aline, Clarence & friends (Box 23, Folder 121)
  - 7 prints '1000 Years' Aline, Clarence & friends (Box 23, Folder 122)
  - 11 color prints '1000 Years' Clarence, springtime c. 1943-44 (Box 23, Folder 123)
  - 6 color prints California, C. S .. Stein, friend 1943-44 (Box 23, Folder 124)
  - 2 prints 3 friends £.1920-30 (Box 23, Folder 125)
  - 3 prints '1000 Years' Yorktown, NY restoration in progress c.1940 (Box 23, Folder 126)
  - 3 prints rural American architecture barns & farmhouses, Mid-Atlantic c. 1930-1940 (Box 23, Folder 127)
  - 1 print front façade [chapel at Balboa Park? San Diego (Box 23, Folder 128)
  - 1 duplicate of #128 (Box 23, Folder 129)
  - 13 prints U.S.S.R., 1927 trip farms, buildings, animals, equipment 1927 (Box 23, Folder 130)
  - Sprints U.S.S.R., trip, people, animals, equipment 1927 (Box 23, Folder 131)
  - 8 prints Constantinople (Istanbul) 1927 (Box 23, Folder 132)
  - 8 prints St. Sophia, market (bazaar), Muslim cemetery [Aline] 1927 (Box 23, Folder 133)
  - 7 prints Bali, East Indies, dancers, architecture c. 1935-36 (Box 23, Folder 134)
  - 3 prints C. S. Stein leading a tour of a planned community [Radburn?] c.1940 (Box 23, Folder 135)
  - 1 print friend c.1925-30 (Box 23, Folder 136)
  - 1 print Aline MacMahon Stein in garden [Middle East] (Box 23, Folder 137)
  - 9 prints Nancy? France (Box 23, Folder 138)
  - 1 print boy with photo album 1921 (Box 23, Folder 139)
  - 1 print & text AIA Gold Medal 1956 (Box 23, Folder 140)
  - 1 print Europe, art student painting, cobblestone street, signed "HW" "Bruges" 1926 (Box 23, Folder 141)
  - 18 contact prints 'Thousand Years' c. 1937-41 (Box 23, Folder 143)
  - 2 enlarged prints interiors of Fieldston School, Riverdale-on-Hudson, N.Y.C., Stein & Kohn architects (Box 23, Folder 144)
  - 3 enlarged prints black & white glossy, Fieldston School, exterior views buildings and landscaping (Box 23, Folder 145)
  - 1 print site plan of Fieldston School ethical culture schools (Box 23, Folder 146)
  - 1 print (enlargement) exterior of Fieldston entrance (Box 23, Folder 147)
  - 2 duplicates of #147 (Box 23, Folder 148)
  - 2 enlarged prints exterior views; of Fieldston School (Box 23, Folder 149)
  - Photo print [postcard] S. Marco, Venice (Box 23, Folder 150)
  - 2 prints Paris, Pont de la Concorde June 1950 (Box 23, Folder 152)
  - 6 prints Paris, Cahillot June 1950 (Box 23, Folder 153)
  - 5 prints Paris, Place des Vosges June 1950 (Box 23, Folder 154)
  - 1 print Paris, Square de Vert Gallant June 1950 (Box 23, Folder 155)
  - 2 prints Paris, Cour La Reine June 1950 (Box 23, Folder 156)
  - 9 envelopes containing "1000 Years" prints ca. 1941
    - 1) gathering of friends at restored property 17 prints late 1941 (Box 23, Folder 157)
    - 2) family & friends/5 prints summer 1941 (Box 23, Folder 158)
    - 3) gathering of friends at restored property/8 prints late winter (Box 23, Folder 159)
    - 4) winter, snow/1 enlargement Jan. 1941 (Box 23, Folder 160)
    - 5) restoration work under way/2 prints c.1940. (Box 23, Folder 161)
    - 6) Family and friends, new dwelling, builder/6 prints summer (Box 23, Folder 162)
    - 7) interior/1 print (Box 23, Folder 163)
    - 8) small structure on the property/1 print (Box 23, Folder 164)
    - 9) the land/5 prints (Box 23, Folder 165)
  - 14 envelopes contain Paris prints from [1950] trip 1950
    - Paris-1 River Seine/urban bridges, riverbank barges/3 prints (Box 23, Folder 166)
    - Paris-2 River Seine/4 prints matte vellum (Box 23, Folder 167)
    - Paris-3 River Seine/3 prints matte vellum (Box 23, Folder 168)
    - Paris-4 Versailles, Grand Trianon/1 print matte vellum (Box 23, Folder 169)
    - Paris-5 streets, arches, bridge and Seine/ 4 prints matte vellum (Box 23, Folder 170)
    - Paris-6 Museum and Eiffel Tower/4 prints matte vellum (Box 23, Folder 171)
    - Paris-7 looking down into urban spaces/6 prints matte vellum (Box 23, Folder 172)
    - Paris -8 open urban spaces/5 prints matte vellum (Box 23, Folder 173)
    - Paris-9 parks/5 prints matte vellum (Box 23, Folder 174)
    - Paris-10 Place de la Concorde (?) /4 prints glossy (Box 23, Folder 175)
    - Paris-11 urban scenes/6 prints glossy (Box 23, Folder 176)
    - Paris-12 ("CH" on back) back waterways, deteriorating houses, aerial (?)/5 prints (Box 23, Folder 177)
    - Paris-13 fountain, Seine, arches/4 prints glossy (Box 23, Folder 178)
    - Paris-14 Chartres/1 print glossy (Box 23, Folder 179)
  - 21 contact prints dancing and ceremonial China or Bali, 1936 (Box 23, Folder 180)
  - 4 prints Tucson, Arizona Lillie Mayer on guest ranch, 1943 (Box 23, Folder 181)
  - 2 prints C. S. Stein and Si Tucson, Arizona, guest ranch, 1943 (Box 23, Folder 182)
  - 6 prints Tucson, Arizona, 1943 (Box 23, Folder 183)
  - 3 black and white guest ranch photo postcard: Tucson, area, c. 1943 (Box 23, Folder 184)
  - 1 small print unidentified woman, c. 1900 (Box 23, Folder 185)
  - Slides (unsorted) (Box 24)
  - Paul A. Rie House, Port Washington, L.I., N.Y., 10 photographs, 2 plans, 1922 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Hudson Guild Farm, Andover, N.J., 11 photographs, 2 negatives, 1 plan, 1930 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - California State Bldg., Balboa Park, San Diego, Cal., 8 photographs, 1915 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Golden Wedding Anniv. Invitation, Leo & Rose Stein, [Design by Clarence Stein], Park West Hospital, Print of Rendering [by C.S. Stein], 1928 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Jefferson Trust Co., Hoboken, N.J., 5 photographs, 1 plan, 1926 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Pasadena Art Institute(proposed), Pasadena, California, 4 photographs, 1 plan, 1927; [see also mapcase folder] (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Wasser House, N.Y., N.Y., 4 photographs, 2 plans, 1923 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Chatham Village, Pittsburgh, Pa., 1 photo of rendering, 1932 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Fresh Meadow Park (proposed) 2 photographs of rendering, 1944 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Phipps Garden Apartments, Queens, N.Y., 5 photographs, 1 plan, 1931-1936 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Temple of Religion, New York World's Fair, 7 photographs, 1 photo of plan, 1939 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Carmelitos Housing, Long Beach, Cal., 1 photo of plan, 1 aerial, 1939 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Wichita Art Inst., Wichita, Ks., 3 photographs of renderings, 5 site plans, 1 plan, 1935 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Hillside Homes, Bronx, N.Y., 1 aerial rendering, 1 photo, 1935 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Ladies Home Journal, proposed model of superblock, 1 photo of plan, 1945 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Fieldston School (Ethical Culture School), Riverdale-on-Hudson, 1 photo, 1932 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Radburn, N.J., Terrace Apts., N.W. & S.W. Residential Districts, 1 rendering, 2 site plans, 1928 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Columbus Circle, N.Y., N.Y., w/ Michael Nowicki, 4 plans, 4 sketches, 1949 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Walter Pollak residence, near Morristown, NJ, 2 photographs, 1930 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Radburn photographs aerial view (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Town Plans of Kitimat, B.C., 13 plans, February 25, 1952 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Master economic chart for C.S. Stein's towns & residential complexes from 1911 to 1945 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Regional city charts, 6 charts, January & June 1954 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - photographs of Mrs. King's house, ca. 1940 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Photographs: family, friends, associates (Box 43, Folder 24)
- Series VIII. Reprints and Articles of Other Professional Planners
  - Abrams, Charles "U.S. Housing: A New Program,"; "Criticism of U.S. Housing: A New Program by Charles Abrams" C.S. Stein, c. 1958 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Ackerman, Frederick L. "Population Expectations, Zoning, Appraisals and Debt."; "The Technologist Looks at the Depression"; "The Facts Behind Technology"; "The Operating Characteristics of Our Productive Economy" "Nine Photographs of the New Hudson River Budge", 1932-1934, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Adams, Frederick J. "Urban Planning Education in The United States", c. 1954 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - American Institute of Architects, Journal "Cities on the Moon", 1966 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Aronovici, Carol "Civic Art"; "Urbanism -- Its Coming of Age"; "Let The Cities Perish"; "The Planner's Five-Foot Shelf", 1932, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Bacon, Edmund N. "Downtown Philadelphia: A Lesson in Design For Urban Growth", 1961 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Balland, W.F.R. "Spacefield -- A Princeton Thesis", 1932 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Barnett, Jonathan "College Buildings Should be Part of Unified Campus Design"; "A Visit to Pihlajamake", 1965 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Bauer, Catharine "Standards As to Labor Relations and Working Conditions in Federally-Aided Community Housing Projects" (no date) "Survey of Community Housing Developments in New York City and Vicinity with Reference to Community Equipment" 1933 "Housing and the Future of Cities in the San Francisco Bay Area" 1963 "Renewal, And the Future Pattern of Living and Working" 1961 "Slums Aren't Necessary" 1934 "Cities in Flux " 1943 "Prize Essay -- Art in Industry" 1931 "Housing Policy and the Educational System" 1955 "The Pattern of Urban and Economic Development: Social Implications" 1956 "Do Americans Hate Cities" 1957 "Leadership Responsibility in Planning for Human Needs" 1957 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Bauer, Catherine, and Lewis Mumford, Lee F. Johnson and Charles Abrams "Housing For America: A Ten-Year Program"Bauer, Catherine, and Eugene Klaber, Samuel Ratens "Planned Large-Scale Housing", 1941 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Bing, Alexander M. "Minimum Costs For Low-Rental Apartments", 1929 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Black, Russell Van Nest "Theory of Planning The Region As Exemplified By the Philadelphia Tri-State Plan"; "Planning for the Small American City", 1930, 1933 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Boardman, Walter S. "What Lies Ahead For The Appalachian Trail?", 1961 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Braines, Simon and John P. Dean "City People On The Move", 1948 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Brownlow, Louis: "Some Problems In New Planning"; "Housing Recollections", 1929, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Buttenheim, Harold S. "If Henry George Were Writing Today", 1935 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Buttenheim and Cornick, Phillip H. "Land Reserves For American Cities", 1938 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Carlson, Eric: "Cooperative Housing In Urban Redevelopment"; "Cooperative Housing by Experts"; "Cooperative Housing", 1951 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Chapin, Stuart F.: "How Big Should A City Be?"; "The Effects of Slum Clearance And Rehousing On Family and Community Relationships In Minneapolis"; "Letter To The Editor", 1938, 1950, 1951 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Churchill, Henry: "Some Reflections on Planning" 1949; "Secondhand Bookshelf" (no date); "Notes on a French Hour #11" 1963; "Notes on a French Hour" 1959; "Notes on a French Hour-" (2nd part) 1959; "A Three Week Expert's Report on the USSR" 1959; "Art And Society Part One" 1957; "Art And Society Part Two" 1957; "Henry Wright: 1878-1939" (no date); "Indefinite Architecture For An Indefinite Period" 1957, 1949-1963, unadted (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Community Planning Review, a quarterly publication "Urban Environment", 1971 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Creese, Walker (Univ. of Oregon, Dean of Architecture School): "The Planning Theories of Sir Raymond Unwin, 1863-1940"; "Parker and Unwin: Architects of Totality", 1963 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - DeMars, Vernon: "Co-operative Housing -- An Appraisal" 1951; "Look Homeward, Housing! " 1946; "Student Center University of California Berkeley Campus" c. 1957; "Row Housing: Can It Solve the Builder's No. 1 Problem?" 1955; "Captions for Illustrations for Education and the Evolving City" 1944, 1944-1957 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Other "Planned Chaos on. the Piazza -- criticism" by Temko, Allan, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Doxiadis, Constantinos: "Ekistics: The Science of Human Settlements" 1959; "Dynapolis: The City of the Future" 1960, 1959-1960 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Other Ehrenkrantz, Ezra and Ogden Tanver, "The Remarkable Dr. Doxiadis" 1961; Clayton, James "The Remarkable Cruise of the New Hellas" 1963, 1961-1963 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Eberlin, Ralph (L.E. Site Planning and Engineering NYC) "Seminar On Public Housing Design", 1949 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Feiss, Carl (Writings of Friends) "The Planned Community: A North American Heritage" 1949; "New Towns for America" 1960, 1949, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Frank, Lawrence K. "Man's Multidimensional Environment", 1943 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Fulmer, O. Kline "Greenbelt", no date (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Gaus, John "Education For The Emerging Field of Regional Planning And Development", 1950 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Glikson, Artur (Recreational Land Use, etc.): "Man -- Region -- World" 1967; "L'Oeuvre D'Artur Glikson" 1966; "Aspects of Man's Relationship to Environment" (no date); "Recreational Land Use" 1955; "The Planner Geddes" 1954, 1954-1967 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Gutheim, Frederick: "Alvar Aalto Today" 1963; "Designing Inter-City Growth" 1962; "The Labor Force" 1956, 1956-1963 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Haskell, Douglas: "Architecture Slum Unclearance 1933; "Bringing Shelter Up To Date: Saying It With Streamlines" 1934; "Bringing Shelter Up To Date: Unchaining House from Land" 1934; "Bringing Shelter Up To Date: Why Don't We Do It?" 1934, 1933-1934 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Holden, Arthur C.: "Stabilized Modernization" 1935; "The Menace Of Mortgage Debts" 1933; "A Basis For Procedure In Slum Clearance" 1933; "Primer of Housing" 1927, 1927-1935 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Holford, William (Prof, of Town Planning, University of Liverpool): "Civic Design", 1948 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Howard, Ebenezer: "Garden Cities of Tomorrow" Japanese Edition 1968 -- Translator's Postscript Translation from German Edition 1968, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - International Federation For Housing And Planning Bulletin: "Sir Raymond Unwin" 1963; "Delos, 1963" 1963; "Bigger Cities Or More Cities?" 1963; "Israel's Kibbueim" 1963; "Land Problems And Regional Planning in Europe" 1966, 1963-1966 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Jacobs, Jane "Modern City Planning: The Victory Over Vitality", 1961 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Kizer, Benjamin H. "Regional Planning In The Columbia River Area", 1951 (Box 18, Folder 37)